Lynley Aldridge

lynley.aldridge@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Social scientist. PhD qualified research and evaluation analyst with over seven years' workplace research experience coordinating a variety of quantitative and qualitative projects to successful completion. Strong communicator with proven analytical and problem-solving skills. Proficient in data collection, data management, and data analysis (using SPSS, R, Excel, NVivo, and SAS Enterprise Guide).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Officer May 2017-Feb 2020 AimHigh; Division of Equity, Diversity and Inclusion; University of New South Wales (Australia)

- Monitoring and evaluation of educational outreach initiatives (designing quantitative and qualitative data collection tools and dashboards; conducting interviews and focus groups; cleaning and analysing data; and reporting findings and recommendations).
- Analysis and modelling of trends in university application, offer, and enrolment data (identifying data sources; extracting, manipulating, and analysing data using SAS Enterprise Guide/ Excel).
- Using data to advocate for changes to institutional policy and practice to improve access and outcomes for disadvantaged students.

Teaching Assistant/ Workshop Tutor Jan 2013-May 2013 School of Sociology & Social Policy, University of Leeds (UK)

• Workshop tutor for second year Research Methods module (quantitative analysis using SPSS).

Project Coordinator

School of Psychology, University of Sydney (Australia) Mar 2012-Aug 2012

• Coordinated a complex multi-stranded systematic literature review on suffering in cancer through to on-schedule completion.

Project Coordinator Jan 2008-Sept 2010

School of Psychology, University of Sydney (Australia)

- Coordinated a complex multi-site study recruiting and surveying migrant cancer patients.
- Liaising and negotiating with Cancer Registry staff, stakeholders, and participants to set up and implement the study.
- Drafting ethics and funding applications and reports, and study protocol and procedures.
- Budgeting and sourcing additional funding.
- Data management and analysis (quantitative and qualitative) using advanced skills in Access, Excel, SPSS, and NVivo.
- Training and supervising a small team of bilingual research assistants.
- Presenting at national and international conferences and contributing to manuscripts.

Research Assistant Feb 2006-Dec 2007 School of Psychology, University of Sydney (Australia)

- Facilitated the smooth running of a longitudinal study of women with ovarian cancer and their partners/carers. The study recruited over 1000 participants from 21 sites.
- Data management and analysis using advanced skills in Access. Excel. and SPSS.
- Responsible for day to day study administration (e.g., sending questionnaires, processing incoming mail, data entry, telephone contact with participants etc).

Lynley Aldridge – Research and Evaluation Analyst Page **2** of **2**

EDUCATION

PhD Sociology 2012 – 2017

University of Leeds (UK)

The overseas working holiday and graduate employment trajectories: A cross-cultural comparison

MA Sociological Research (with Distinction) 2010 – 2011

University of Essex (UK)

B Psychology (Hons, Class 1) 1998 – 2003

Charles Sturt University (Australia)

Grad Dip Japanese 1995 – 1996

Hiroshima University (Japan)

B Japanese 1993 – 1996

Wollongong University (Australia)

AWARDS

• University of Leeds Fully-Funded International Research Scholarship

- Japan Foundation Endowment Committee grant of £3,300 to support PhD fieldwork in Japan
- Fuller Postgraduate Prize, University of Essex best overall performance in coursework & thesis
- School of Social Sciences and Liberal Studies (Honours) Scholarship, Charles Sturt University

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

Detailed list available upon request.

I have two first-authored peer-reviewed publications and am co-author on a further fourteen. I have presented at national and international conferences, including as an invited speaker. I have led workshops on the use of Access, Excel and Endnote to facilitate research.

Aldridge L. (2014). Overseas gap years and working holidays in the UK and Japan: Insights from a comparative approach. 18th ISA World Congress of Sociology, 13-19 July 2014, Yokohama, Japan.

Aldridge L, McGrane J, et al. (2010). Unmet needs in Chinese (Mandarin and Cantonese), Greek and Arabic-speaking cancer survivors in Australia. International Psycho-Oncology Society 12th World Congress of Psycho-Oncology, 25-29 May 2010, Quebec, Canada.

Best M, **Aldridge L**, et al. (2014). Assessment of spiritual suffering in the cancer context: A systematic literature review. <u>Palliative & Supportive Care</u>, **13**(5), 1335-61.

Butow P, **Aldridge L**, et al. (2013). Inferior health-related quality of life and psychological well-being in immigrant cancer survivors: A population-based study. <u>European Journal of Cancer</u>, **49**(8), 1948-56.

Butow P, Bell M, **Aldridge L**, et al. (2013). Unmet needs in immigrant cancer survivors: A cross-sectional population-based study. <u>Supportive Care in Cancer</u>, **21**(9), 2509-20.

Aldridge LJ, Islam MR. (2012). Cultural differences in athlete attributions for success and failure: The sports pages revisited. <u>International Journal of Psychology</u>. **47**(1): 67-75.

Aldridge L. (2011). Integrating immediate context and enduring dispositions in the explanation of action: An illustration using 'Gone with the Wind'. <u>The Essex Graduate Journal of Sociology</u>. **11**: 42-52.